Guide to the Doris Duke Papers, 1798-2003 and undated (bulk 1930-1999)
Duke University. University Archives
- Subject Files, 1905-2004 and undated
  - Medical, 1950-1994 (bulk 1992-1993)
    - X-Rays, Head and Neck (14 total), 1982 Jul 21 (Oversize-box 282, Folder 7)
    - X-Rays, Chest and Pelvis (3 total), 1982 Nov 17 (Oversize-box 282, Folder 8)
    - X-Rays, Both Knees (5 total), 1985 Aug 21 (Oversize-box 283, Folder 1)
    - X-Rays, Neck (10 copies) and Right Hand (5 copies) (15 total), 1986 Feb 23 (Oversize-box 283, Folder 2)
    - X-Rays, Cervical Thoracic, Left Clavicle, and Left Shoulder (6 total), 1986 Jun 23 (Oversize-box 283, Folder 3)
    - X-Rays, Left Knee, Right Knee, and Cervical (17 total), 1990 Jun 29 (1 of 4) (Oversize-box 284, Folder 1)
    - X-Rays, Left Knee, Right Knee, and Cervical (17 total), 1990 Jun 29 (2 of 4) (Oversize-box 284, Folder 2)
    - X-Rays, Left Knee, Right Knee, and Cervical (17 total), 1990 Jun 29 (3 of 4) (Oversize-box 284, Folder 3)
    - X-Rays, Left Knee, Right Knee, and Cervical (17 total), 1990 Jun 29 (4 of 4) (Oversize-box 284, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1905-1993
    The materials in this subseries vary widely and serve to document general subjects related to Doris Duke that are not documented in the other subseries. It is the only subseries that includes materials from Doris Duke's childhood such as her school composition books, homework assignments, and glossy photographs/scrapbooks of magazine clippings of actors and actresses from the 1920s. Other materials included are notes and lyrics written by Doris Duke, original dress designs from the House of Paquin for Doris Duke, Playbills from shows attended by Doris Duke, and newspaper clippings organized by Doris Duke that were of interest to her. Inside these folders are the spines of the binders (paper) with her handwriting on how they were separated. Of interest is the "Me" binder (folder) which contains clippings about Doris Duke.
    RESTRICTED: Access to one folder in Box 373 is restricted and requires prior written approval from the Doris Duke Charitable Foundation to view.
    - Postcards to Mrs. DA Smith and Margaret Smith, circa 1905 (Oversize-box 285)
    - Doris Duke's celebrity scrapbook, "Paramount Pep Club", 1924 Mar 7 (Oversize-box 286)
    - Homework assignments of Doris Duke. Includes paintings and artwork completed by Doris Duke. Found in a folder labelled "Scrap book", 1924 (Box 287, Folder 1)
    - Doris Duke's grade school compositions, circa 1920s (1 of 2) (Box 287, Folder 2)
    - Doris Duke's grade school compositions, circa 1920s (2 of 2) (Box 287, Folder 3)
    - Glossy photographs of actors/actresses, primarily movie stills, circa 1920s (1 of 2) (Box 287, Folder 4)
    - Glossy photographs of actors/actresses, primarily movie stills, circa 1920s (2 of 2) (Box 287, Folder 5)
    - Postcards addressed to Doris Duke/with Doris Duke's handwriting, circa 1920s and undated (Box 287, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper/magazine clippings of various movie actors and actresses, circa 1920a (Box 288, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper/magazine clippings primarily of Rudolph Valentino, circa 1920s (1 of 2) (Box 288, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper/magazine clippings primarily of Rudolph Valentino, circa 1920s (2 of 2) (Box 288, Folder 3)
    - Doris Duke's celebrity scrapbook, circa 1920s (Box 288, Folder 4)
    - Doris Duke's celebrity scrapbook, circa 1920s (Box 288, Folder 5)
    - Prints of Roman statues and buildings kept by Doris Duke when she was in school, circa 1920s (Box 289, Folder 1)
    - "Me" - Doris Duke personal clippings, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 289, Folder 2)
    - Specifications and special features for an Aerocar to be built in accordance with Curtiss Aerocar Company's drawing SK-190. Includes orders for a Curtiss Aerocar, 1936 (Box 289, Folder 3)
    - Memoranda and invitations to art and exhibition openings, 1936-1937, 1981, 1990 (Box 289, Folder 4)
    - Lyrics, possibly to the Hawaiian recordings in the Vinyl Recordings Collection of Doris Duke, 1942 Aug 17 (Box 289, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous magazines; one featuring Doris Duke, 1942 and undated (Box 289, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clipping of possible friend/associate of Doris Duke's, circa 1940s (Box 289, Folder 7)
    - People - clippings and photographs, circa 1940s-1991 (Box 289, Folder 8)
    - Theatre programs and Playbills, presumably from shows attended by Doris Duke, 1952-1957 and undated (1 of 2) (Box 289, Folder 9)
    - Theatre programs and Playbills, presumably from shows attended by Doris Duke, 1952-1957 and undated (2 of 2) (Box 289, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Doris Duke business cards. Eduardo Tirella, etal. Includes receipts for storage of furs and other goods, 1953-1954 (Box 289, Folder 11)
    - Notes written by Doris Duke, circa 1954 (Box 289, Folder 12)
    - Article, "Unknown Life of Jesus Christ by the Discovery of the Manuscript Nicolas Notovich." Translated from the French by Alexina Loranger, 1955 (Box 289, Folder 13)
    - Dress designs (includes fabric swatches) from the House of Paquin, presumably made for Doris Duke, circa 1930s-1940s (Oversize-box 290)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, invoices, and inventory, 1955-1958 and undated (Box 291, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous lyrics to many of the Hawaiian recordings in the Vinyl Recordings Collection of Doris Duke. Writer uncertain, circa 1950s (Box 291, Folder 2)
    - Fabric samples to be used for clothing for Miss Duke designed by Balenciaga. In French, 1961 (Box 291, Folder 3)
    - Singing instructions from Sid Shaw to Doris Duke, 1967 (Box 291, Folder 4)
    - Certificate from NYU, Institute of Fine Arts (IFA) enabling Doris Duke to take pictures of Mogul Architecture while in Kashmir on behalf of IFA. Includes and invoice from Preco Studios Ltd in Srinagar, Kashmir for work performed for Doris Duke's IFA photo shoot, 1969 (Box 291, Folder 5)
    - Family - clippings, circa 1960s-1991 (Box 291, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings for clothing and other items that Doris Duke purchased or wanted to purchase, 1975-1980 (Box 291, Folder 7)
    - Self-Realization Fellowship, booklet on meditation and life, 1977 Spring (Box 291, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes and newspaper clippings, 1977-1978 and undated (Box 291, Folder 9)
    - Books ordered for Doris Duke, 1979-1981 (Box 291, Folder 10)
    - Fabric samples, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 291, Folder 11)
    - Notes, business cards, and miscellaneous documents, 1980-1993 and undated (Box 291, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, brochures and other materials kept by Doris Duke, 1981-1985 and undated (Box 291, Folder 13)
    - Birthday cards sent to Johnny Gomez, 1982 Nov (Box 291, Folder 14)
    - Kathy Orentreich’s admission essay to Duke University’s School of Medicine. Ms. Orentreich wrote to Miss Duke asking for her help to be admitted to the school, 1982 (Box 291, Folder 15)
    - Sotheby's sales results, 1984, 1990 (Box 291, Folder 16)
    - Receipts for unknown purches, 1987 (Box 291, Folder 17)
    - Business cards for contacts/associates/merchants of Doris Duke, 1980s (Box 291, Folder 18)
    - Flyer and correspondence regarding genetically engineered food, circa 1980s (Box 291, Folder 19)
    - The Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin" (Spring 1993) and "Opportunities in American Antiquities" (January 1991), 1991, 1993 (Box 292, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 292, Folder 2)
    - Memorial tribute to Thomas Ammann, 1993 Nov 18 (Box 292, Folder 3)
    - Invitation to a private viewing of the new Chanel collection, 1993 (Box 292, Folder 4)
    - Obituaries on Doris Duke and articles regarding her will, 1993 (Box 292, Folder 5)
    - Contact information for Doris Duke's personal and professional contacts, undated (Box 292, Folder 6)
    - Doris Duke's business cards, undated (Box 292, Folder 7)
    - Doris Duke's notes on telephone calls she wanted to make, undated (Box 292, Folder 8)
    - Doris Duke's personal address book with Doris Duke's handwriting, undated (Box 292, Folder 9)
    - Handwritten notes/lyrics by Doris Duke, undated (Box 292, Folder 10)
    - Horoscope created specifically for Doris Duke, undated (Box 292, Folder 11)
    - List of foods to be kept in Doris Duke's kitchen. Includes a recipe for braised endives, undated (Box 292, Folder 12)
    - Lyrics written by Doris Duke, undated (Box 292, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous maps and guidebooks, undated (1 of 2) (Box 292, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous maps and guidebooks, undated (2 of 2) (Box 292, Folder 15)
    - Notes and music in Doris Duke's hand, undated (Box 292, Folder 16)
    - Photographs of jewelry and jewelry catalogs, undated (Box 292, Folder 17)
    - Play, "Fancy, Fancy", undated (Box 293, Folder 1)
    - Random writings and sketches possibly done by Doris Duke, undated (Box 293, Folder 2)
    - Travel postcards, undated (1 of 3) (Box 293, Folder 3)
    - Travel postcards, undated (2 of 3) (Box 293, Folder 4)
    - Travel postcards, undated (3 of 3) (Box 293, Folder 5)
    - Horoscope of female, born Friday, November 22, 1912: 7:30 A.M., New York City, 1912 (Box 364, Folder 1)
    - Book-Riverside Literature Series "The Courtship of Miles Standish: Elizabeth", owned by Doris Duke, circa 1920s (Box 364, Folder 2)
    - Duke University Chanticleer-personalized for Doris Duke, 1926 (Box 364, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper article about Barbara Hutton's debut, 1930 Nov 14 (Box 364, Folder 4)
    - Article, "A XVth Century Persian Painting on Silk", by Arthur Upham Pope, 1934 Oct (Box 364, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous materials-some personal correspondence, recipes, 1936-1979 (1 of 2) (Box 364, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous materials-some personal correspondence, recipes, 1936-1979 (2 of 2) (Box 364, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (copy) from Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1937 Dec 29 (Box 364, Folder 8)
    - Various financial statements for Doris Duke Cromwell, including stocks owned, trial balances, and Hillsborough Township Tax Case, 1939-1941 (Box 364, Folder 9)
    - Article by Cecil Beaton, "Personal Portraits of Film Stars", circa 1940s (Box 364, Folder 10)
    - Religious Story "The Yogu Sutras of Patanjali", by Paramhansa Yoganada, 1944 Mar 26 (Box 364, Folder 11)
    - Magazine article from Time Magazine featuring Rosanna Seaborn Todd, 1955, May 23 (Box 364, Folder 12)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (1 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 1)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (2 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 2)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (3 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 3)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (4 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 4)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (5 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 5)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (6 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 6)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (7 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 7)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (8 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 8)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (9 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 9)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of City Bank Farmers Trust Company as Successor Trustee of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917, 1955 (10 of 10) (Box 365, Folder 10)
    - Summary Statement of the account of the Proceedings of James B. Duke of the trust created by James B. Duke for the benefit of Doris Duke under Indenture of Trust dated May 2, 1917 and covering the period from May 2, 1917 through October 10, 1925, 1955 (Box 366, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper article, "Old Home Place Put on Auction Block". Article discusses the sale of Malabar Farms, circa 1956 (Box 366, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper article on Sophie van Senden Theis's death and her service to the Child Adoption Committee of the State Charities Aid Association, 1957 Apr 10 (Box 366, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlet, "The Secret of Yoga: A Story of Hinduism," by Douglas Low, 1960 (Box 366, Folder 4)
    - Handwritten lyrics by Doris Duke. Includes music and lyrics to "Bossa Nova All the Way," by Joe Castro. Also includes commercial recording songbooks, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 366, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1960-1985 and undated (Box 366, Folder 6)
    - Letter from George Jay and Associates regarding Clover Records, circa 1960s (Box 366, Folder 7)
    - Sohio Petroleum Company, 1963 (Box 366, Folder 8)
    - Letter from George Nassan to Doris Duke. Includes black and white photographs, 1965 Dec 11 (Box 366, Folder 9)
    - Annual report for the Animal Medical Center for FY 1966, 1967 (Box 366, Folder 10)
    - Letter from Skrebneski Photography about dentures, 1968 Jul 25 (Box 366, Folder 11)
    - "Little Dukes" Central NJ July 4th Parade. Includes black and white photographs, 1968 (Box 366, Folder 12)
    - JODO, Inc. and Clover Records Enterprises Fund Req. No. 1, 1965 Dec-1968 Apr (1 of 5) (Box 366, Folder 13)
    - JODO, Inc. and Clover Records Enterprises Fund Req. No. 1, 1965 Dec-1968 Apr (2 of 5) (Box 366, Folder 14)
    - JODO, Inc. and Clover Records Enterprises Fund Req. No. 1, 1965 Dec-1968 Apr (3 of 5) (Box 367, Folder 1)
    - JODO, Inc. and Clover Records Enterprises Fund Req. No. 1, 1965 Dec-1968 Apr (4 of 5) (Box 367, Folder 2)
    - JODO, Inc. and Clover Records Enterprises Fund Req. No. 1, 1965 Dec-1968 Apr (5 of 5) (Box 367, Folder 3)
    - Letter regarding the selling of a painting of Napolean to Doris Duke that would compliment the portrait she purchased at Christie's in 1969, 1970 (Box 367, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings regarding topics such as art shows, furniture, and Middle East, 1970, 1979-1993 (Box 367, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding the Duke Employee Pension Plan, 1970-1974 (Box 367, Folder 6)
    - Near East Dance Foundation, Inc. Voucher Book #1, 1971 Aug-1972 Sep (1 of 4) (Box 367, Folder 7)
    - Voucher Record, Doris Duke, 1968-1973 May (1 of 4) (Box 368, Folder 1)
    - Voucher Record, Doris Duke, 1968-1973 May (2 of 4) (Box 368, Folder 2)
    - Voucher Record, Doris Duke, 1968-1973 May (3 of 4) (Box 368, Folder 3)
    - Voucher Record, Doris Duke, 1968-1973 May (4 of 4) (Box 368, Folder 4)
    - Near East Dance Foundation, Inc. Voucher Book #1, 1971 Aug-1972 Sep (2 of 4) (Box 369, Folder 1)
    - Near East Dance Foundation, Inc. Voucher Book #1, 1971 Aug-1972 Sep (3 of 4) (Box 369, Folder 2)
    - Near East Dance Foundation, Inc. Voucher Book #1, 1971 Aug-1972 Sep (4 of 4) (Box 369, Folder 3)
    - Organizational chart of the Animal Medical Center, 1972 (Box 369, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and other material related to the Animal Medical Center, 1972-1974 (Box 369, Folder 5)
    - Near East Dance Foundation, Inc. Voucher Book #2, 1972 Sep-1974 Jul (1 of 3) (Box 369, Folder 6)
    - Near East Dance Foundation, Inc. Voucher Book #2, 1972 Sep-1974 Jul (2 of 3) (Box 369, Folder 7)
    - Near East Dance Foundation, Inc. Voucher Book #2, 1972 Sep-1974 Jul (3 of 3) (Box 370, Folder 1)
    - Invoices for LADD Interiors, 1972-1980 (Box 370, Folder 2)
    - Materials related to antique purchases, 1973-1974 (Box 370, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence to Harry Cox, 1974 (Box 370, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous address books belonging to Doris Duke, 1974 and undated (Box 370, Folder 5)
    - Unsolicited letters to Doris Duke, 1974-1975 (1 of 2) (Box 370, Folder 6)
    - Unsolicited letters to Doris Duke, 1974-1975 (2 of 2) (Box 370, Folder 7)
    - Letter from Rear Admiral Neill Phillips, 1976 Jul 17 (Box 370, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous letters to Doris Duke, 1976 (1 of 2) (Box 370, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous letters to Doris Duke, 1976 (2 of 2) (Box 370, Folder 10)
    - Sheet Music, "This Masquerade," by Leon Russell, 1976 (Box 371, Folder 1)
    - Unsolicited letters to Doris Duke, 1977 (1 of 4) (Box 371, Folder 2)
    - Unsolicited letters to Doris Duke, 1977 (2 of 4) (Box 371, Folder 3)
    - Unsolicited letters to Doris Duke, 1977 (3 of 4) (Box 371, Folder 4)
    - Unsolicited letters to Doris Duke, 1977 (4 of 4) (Box 371, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous materials related to Doris Duke, including her waist and hip measurements, 1977 (Box 371, Folder 6)
    - Handwritten notes by Doris Duek mostly about music. Includes copies of images of architectural drawings of maps and a nightly checklist and instructions for running Falcon Lair, 1977-1992 (Box 371, Folder 7)
    - Design specifications for door at NYU's Near East Center, 1978 May (Box 371, Folder 8)
    - Unsolicited letters to Doris Due, 1978-1981 (1 of 3) (Box 371, Folder 9)
    - Unsolicited letters to Doris Due, 1978-1981 (2 of 3) (Box 372, Folder 1)
    - Unsolicited letters to Doris Due, 1978-1981 (3 of 3) (Box 372, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings, cheese and cream, 1981 (Box 372, Folder 3)
    - Photographs of clothes and other items taken with Doris Duke while travelling, 1983-1984 (1 of 4) (Box 372, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of clothes and other items taken with Doris Duke while travelling, 1983-1984 (2 of 4) (Box 372, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of clothes and other items taken with Doris Duke while travelling, 1983-1984 (3 of 4) (Box 372, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of clothes and other items taken with Doris Duke while travelling, 1983-1984 (4 of 4) (Box 372, Folder 7)
    - Invoices-Helone Arpels, 1984 (Box 373, Folder 1)
    - Invoices and correspondence regarding Mark Forrest West, 1984 (Box 373, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding litigation Patrick J. Mahn vs. Duke, 1985 (Box 373, Folder 3)
    - Note from Quincy Jones to Doris Duke, 1985 (Box 373, Folder 4)
    - Pension Plan listing as of May 1, 1986, 1986 (Box 373, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and reports on performance of Doris Duke's stock and bond portfolios, 1986-1987 (Box 373, Folder 6)
    - Screenplay, "Echoes" by Mac Gudgeon, 1987 Mar (Box 373, Folder 7)
    - Doris Duke Financial Statements, 1988 (Box 373, Folder 8)
    - Memoranda to Doris Duke regarding NY apartment and SEAAC, 1988 (Box 373, Folder 9)
    - Doris Duke Contributions, 1988-1991 (Box 373, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence regarding fire insurance for Trail Blazers Camp, 1989, 1992 (Box 373, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, John and James "Jim" Castro, Joey Castro's sons, circa 1980s (Box 373, Folder 12)
    - Letter to Miss Duke found in Archives Room 1, 1992 (Box 373, Folder 13)
    - Invitation to the inauguration of Nannerl O. Keohane as the 80th president of Duke University, 1993 Oct (Box 373, Folder 14)
    - General correspondence to Doris Duke from acquaintances and unsolicited, 1993 (Box 373, Folder 15)
    - Memoranda from Irwin Bloom to Doris Duke, 1993 (Box 373, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1993 (Box 373, Folder 17)
    - Memoranda relating to Bernard Lafferty's purchase of cockatiels, 1995-1996 (Box 373, Folder 18)
    - Health records, mini horse, Image, 1995-2004 (Box 373, Folder 19)
    - Health records, mini horse, Shadow, 1995-2004 (Box 373, Folder 20)
    - Vaccination certificates (copies) for cats, 2001, 2203 (Box 373, Folder 21)
    - Health records, dogs, Abbott and Costello, 2001-2004 (Box 373, Folder 2)
    - Health records, horse, Dually, 2003-2004 (Box 374, Folder 1)
    - Astrological Horoscope for Doris Duke, undated (Box 374, Folder 2)
    - Bob Timberlake collection card, undated (Box 374, Folder 3)
    - Copies of photographs of Doris Duke with Gilbert Roland, undated (Box 374, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and inventory (including color photographs) related to LADD Interiors, undated (Box 374, Folder 5)
    - Doris Duke handwriting, undated (Box 374, Folder 6)
    - Doris Duke lyrics and music, undated (Box 374, Folder 7)
    - Doris Duke recount (handwritten) of a dream, undated (Box 374, Folder 8)
    - Exercises for the face, presumably designed specifically for Doris Duke, undated (Box 374, Folder 9)
    - Labels removed from records from the Vinyl Recordings collection, undated (Box 374, Folder 10)
    - Lists of clothing owned by Doris Duke. Includes color photographs, undated (Box 374, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous birthday greetings, undated (Box 374, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous travel guides, including Paris, Constantinople, and India, undated (Box 374, Folder 13)
    - Novel/manuscript, "Behind the Dark Glasses," by Bahija Lovejoy with Jane Spangler, undated (1 of 2) (Box 374, Folder 14)
    - Novel/manuscript, "Behind the Dark Glasses," by Bahija Lovejoy with Jane Spangler, undated (2 of 2) (Box 374, Folder 15)
    - Novel, "Surrounded by Theives," by Robert Burnette, undated (Box 374, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified chandelier, undated (Box 374, Folder 17)
    - Book, La Tulipe Noire. "Doris Duke LVC Sappo" written on the inside cover, 1915 (Box 377, Folder 1)
    - Book, Ancient History Atlas. "7734 Doris Duke 7734" written on front cover and "Doris Duke IIIC Room 54" on inside cover, 1916 (Box 377, Folder 2)
    - Book of Psalms. "D. Duke IIIC Room 54" and "This is certainly not as interesting as the Odyssey" written in pencil on the inside cover, 1923 (Box 377, Folder 3)
    - Book, L'Evasion du Duc de Beaufort. "Doris Duke + VC" written on inside cover. Also includes handwritten annotations in English, undated (Box 377, Folder 4)
    - Book, In World Guide. Doris Duke's personal travel book with here initials inscribed on cover, 1977 (Box 377, Folder 5)
    - Letter from Wayne Skjoldal to Doris Duke regarding possible funding for non-profit program, 1989 May 24 (Box 377, Folder 6)
    - Letter from Edward Tabela to Doris Duke regarding possible financial assistance, 1973 Dec (Box 377, Folder 7)
    - Printed material: Decorative plants, 1950-1953 (Box 379, Folder 1)
    - Printed material: Natural and organic farming, 1954-1981 (Box 379, Folder 2)
    - Printed material: Natural food and medicine, 1966-1977 (Box 379, Folder 3)
    - Printed material: Agricultural magazines, 1944-1958 (Box 379, Folder 4)
    - Printed material: U.S. Dept. of Agriculture and N.J. Agricultural Experiment Station, 1928-1953 (Box 379, Folder 5)
    - Copy of J.B. Duke Estate map, 1911 Jan. (Box 379, Folder 6)
    - Bound volumes: Trees, 1905-1962 (Box 379)
    - Bound volumes: Natural and organic farming, 1907-1955 (Box 379)